From up here,
our city looks so big.
Because you've never left it.
Staying in Lecang is actually pretty nice.
By the way,
have you guys thought about where to go to college?
Beijing.
My dreams are calling me.
No matter where I get in,
I'm leaving this place anyway.
No matter where we go,
this will always be our hometown.
I want to leave here
and never come back.
I'm a failure.
Sir.
My mom...
My mom never had a single day of happiness.
She never had a single good day.
Mr. Chen
Take a look. Is this it?
Thank you.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Mom
How did you find it?
I guessed.
Mom
You know,
living in this city has actually been pretty nice all these years.
Yeah, it has.
So I wanted to take a good look before I leave.
Sometimes it feels like so much has changed.
But also like nothing has changed at all.
From up here,
our city looks so big.
Because you've never left it.
I'm getting out of here.
And I'm never coming back.
It's ready. Let's eat.
Let's eat, let's eat.
Here.
Li Yiran.
May your path ahead be smooth.
Why are you being so emotional?
It doesn't even sound like you.
Come on!
My stomach suddenly hurts a bit.
Wait for me a sec.
I'll be right back.
When are you planning to leave?
The day after tomorrow.
Gonna see me off?
I won't have time.
There's a funeral the day after tomorrow.
That won't work then.
Honoring the dead comes first.
That definitely has to be your top priority.
After you leave,
Lecang's funeral industry
will end up with a lot more unsolved mysteries.
Why?
If it weren't for your superpower,
they probably wouldn't have found his bracelet.
That's true.
Isn't there a saying?
Prejudice in people's minds is like a massive mountain.
So when we
stand at the bottom, we can only see its surface.
Actually, I was a bit prejudiced today too.
I thought he was just a greedy, ungrateful son.
Do you know why I don't want to do this job?
Ever since I was little,
I've seen people tear each other apart at funerals.
And I've seen so many life-and-death partings.
I've always felt this job is very...
tragic and soul-crushing.
Well, I'm quite different from you.
At first, I felt that
being able to experience the deceased's past
and their feelings
was like a curse.
But now I feel that
this superpower
is actually more like a blessed gift.
What?
Superpower?
Yiran.
You have superpowers?
Psychometry.
Whenever I touch the belongings of the deceased,
certain sounds, images,
and even smells
will flood into my mind.
I can even feel
the deceased's joys and sorrows.
I can vouch for that.
A Min,
you've lived a long time.
Analyze this for us.
Can you figure anything out?
Before your mother passed away,
she said she wanted some oranges.
You went out and brought some back,
but before she could eat them,
she...
Exactly.
Actually, I've done a lot of research,
but couldn't find a perfect explanation.
There's Zhuangzi's Butterfly Dream,
and Alice in Wonderland Syndrome.
Psychometry.
It sounds pretty mystical,
but the world is vast and full of wonders.
Our understanding
is just the tip of the iceberg.
In this world,
there are indeed some people
whose synesthesia is beyond the ordinary.
For example, Da Vinci,
David Hockney...
These famous artists,
their talents might just stem from this.
So you're saying
Yiran essentially possesses a key
that can unlock the door to the past.
You could also say
Yiran is The Chosen Funeral Director.
For the deceased,
there's always something they want to leave behind
as a memento for the living.
Because a person truly dies
when they are forgotten by the living.
If you can make good use of this gift,
you might be able to do your best
to help these departed souls
fulfill their dying wishes.
A Min,
Yiran is leaving soon.
I'm going back to Shanghai.
Life is full of diverging paths.
It's getting late.
Let me take you home.
A Min.
Thanks for clearing things up for me.
Yiran
I... I want to say a few more words to Yiran.
You're back.
Go wash your hands and eat.
Okay.
So formal?
Once you go to Shanghai,
you won't be able to get such authentic free-range chicken.
I made it just for you.
Quick, try some.
Here.
Don't eat leftovers.
It's bad for your stomach.
I cooked this at noon.
What's wrong with leftovers?
Don't waste it.
Right,
Tang Tang and A Fu asked me to give this to you.
They went to the shop today.
A Fu, Tang Tang!
Welcome back to Joy Bells.
Take a look around, pick whatever you like.
Zhou Fang!
You've already sponsored so much for our wedding.
Now you're spending money again.
We feel so bad.
Taking some photos for you is hardly an expense.
It's fine, don't stress over it.
Just pick what you like.
We'll shoot whichever ones you choose.
Wu!
Come here!
Let me introduce you.
These two are A Fu and Tang Tang.
Hello, I'm Wu Huilian.
I'm happy to help you.
Yeah, she's Huilian.
Yiran's mom.
They know Yiran?
Are you good friends with Yiran?
Huilian.
You know...
If it weren't for Yiran,
our wedding wouldn't have happened.
Everything's fine, why are you crying?
Don't cry, don't cry.
They're about to take their wedding photos.
I'm so happy for them.
Yeah.
So happy for them.
Here.
We definitely need a little drink on such a happy occasion.
Come on.
Eat up.
You working at Joy Bells...
Is work going okay?
More than okay.
I'm practically the backbone.
You're the backbone?
Why are you giving me that doubting look?
I have to tell you all about it.
In all of Lecang,
my matchmaking success rate...
If I claim to be second,
no one dares to claim first.
Plus,
I've got my professional mourning experience, you know.
You don't tell people you mourned professionally while matchmaking, do you?
Am I dumb?
Of course I don't.
What I mean is,
whether mourning for others
or helping people find a match,
they both require...
real emotional investment.
Didn't Chen teach me
to truly listen, see, and feel?
For major life events like these,
I take them very seriously.
Okay.
Seeing your enthusiasm,
I'm relieved.
So,
Yiran,
when you go to Shanghai,
you must work hard.
Make something of yourself.
I believe you can definitely make a name for yourself.
You believe I can make a name for myself?
Absolutely.
You're pretty,
capable,
hardworking,
and you can endure hardship.
If you don't succeed, who will?
Here.
Let's drink to that.
What are you doing?
Here.
New shoes,
new path.
These shoes are so pretty.
Do you want them or not?
If not, I'm returning them.
So stingy!
You're taking back a gift you already gave?
Just try them on.
See if they fit.
Okay.
Perfect fit.
I've never worn shoes that fit so well in my life.
New shoes,
new path.
Stepping toward a new life.
Did you notice?
When I wear these shoes,
it makes my butt look a little perkier.
I didn't notice.
Let me walk a few more laps to show you.
How could you not notice?
Look.
Twist, twist, twist.
Twist, twist.
Really,
these shoes,
I love them so much.
I love them, I love them.
I really, really love them.
I love them, I love them!
I love these shoes so much.
I love these shoes, they're so pretty.
Don't they look good, Lao Li?
Do they look good?
I think they look great.
So pretty.
Pops,
you know what?
I'm living under the same roof with Wu Huilian now.
It seems I'm getting used to it.
But I still think about you often.
I came to say goodbye to you today.
Because tomorrow,
I'll be leaving home once again.
While I was back, I saw many old friends.
I saw your best friend, Daren.
Wait a minute.
Huilian.
Yiran.
Right now,
he runs his own barbecue stand.
But he's just as frugal as before.
He earns money but hates spending it.
And Juan,
she's also still
running that hair salon with Yangyang.
She dresses herself up beautifully every day.
Yangyang has grown up too.
They're doing great.
Oh right, Paradise Funeral Home.
Do you remember Paradise Funeral Home?
They were the ones who handled your funeral.
The road to the netherworld is long, take it slow;
Half awake, half drunk, all sorrows let go.
Pops,
you must bless Chen from heaven.
Bless him with
good health and a long life.
Also, there's a weirdo at Paradise Funeral Home.
His name is A Min.
He doesn't like to smile,
and doesn't talk much either.
He scared me when I first saw him.
I thought, why does he look like a bad guy?
But he's actually very nice.
And he gave me a lot of inspiration.
A person truly dies
when they are forgotten by the living.
Chen's daughter, Xiaofang,
she's my best, best, best friend.
You must bless her with happiness.
Bless her with lots and lots of happiness.
Bless me, Chen Xiaofang, to become a multimillionaire soon!
She has a dream
of becoming a rich young lady.
If possible,
just bless her with sudden wealth too.
And Xiaofang's brother,
Chen Baixi.
He chose to come back from Beijing.
After not seeing him for years,
I feel like he's changed.
Yet it also seems like nothing has changed.
I feel like he's another version of me.
Don't try to persuade me.
Everyone has their own ambitions.
Everyone has their own path to walk.
Actually, when it comes down to it,
the one I worry about the most
is still Wu Huilian.
I know, I know.
I know what you'd say to me if you were here.
You'd definitely try to persuade me again,
saying she's doing it all for my own good.
I understand all of that.
But Pops,
I just haven't figured out how to forgive her yet.
I miss you so much.
I really miss you.
Lao Li.
Yiran and I are doing fine.
I have a new job.
I'm working at that matchmaking company.
It's very stable.
As for Yiran,
she got a new job too.
She's going to Shanghai.
She leaves tomorrow.
Actually, right now,
I'm very content.
I just have a little regret.
She won't call me Mom.
But that's okay.
The two of us
never speak nicely to each other.
I say one thing, she talks back.
But it's good in a way.
All the bickering
makes this house feel alive, right?
Otherwise, without you, it's so empty.
Come on, Lao Li.
Let's have a little drink.
Yiran has had a hard life.
Watch over her from heaven.
As long as she's safe
and healthy, that's enough.
Cheers.
Wu Huilian.
You're drunk again.
Let's go to bed.
Stay a bit.
Just sit with me for a bit.
Yiran,
I know
deep down,
you still hate me.
So,
you never call me Mom.
But that's okay.
You calling me Wu Huilian...
I like hearing that, too.
You can call me whatever you want.
It's been so many years,
and I've never properly told you
I'm sorry.
About what happened eight years ago,
I never expected
things to end up like this.
Stop pretending!
You don't like drinking, huh?
Come on! Come on!
Drink up!
Just drink!
You sure you don't like it?
Drink!
Son of a bitch, that's way out of line!
Mom, Mom, calm down.
Let's call the cops and wait for them.
By the time they arrive, she'll be bullied to death!
Stay out of this.
What are you doing?
What are you doing, son of a bitch?
You filthy men,
why are you bullying a girl?
Stupid bitch, sticking your nose in?
What are you doing?
What do you want?
If you keep bullying her, I'll call the cops!
Call the cops my ass!
She likes to drink!
Come on, drink!
Son of a bitch! What are you doing?
Let her go!
Mom! Mom!
Are you okay?
Pull her away!
Get away!
Son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch! How dare you hit my wife!
And hit my daughter!
I'll kill you!
Hit him!
Get out of the way!
What are you doing?!
Get away!
You're asking for it!
I'll kill you!
Pops! Pops! Pops!
Yiran!
Lao Li!
Son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch
Pops
Lao Li
When I saw that girl
getting bullied by a bunch of guys,
I felt like if I didn't help her,
it would just break my heart.
She was so young.
So, I...
Yiran,
Mom is so sorry.
Lao Li, look.
Go to sleep.
Time for bed.
Let's go.
I'll take you to bed.
Go to sleep.
Damn it
I drank too much again last night.
Take all of these with you.
I made them myself.
Why so much?
Look.
This
is your favorite dried radish.
And this.
Pickled chili bamboo shoots. Great with rice.
And the hotpot base I made for you.
The food in Shanghai is too sweet.
It won't suit your taste.
Did I drink too much again last night?
Hey, Xiaofang.
Yiran, hurry to Paradise Funeral Home.
It's urgent.
What's going on?
You'll see when you get here.
Okay.
Wu Huilian, I'm not eating!
I'm heading out!
Wait!
Grab something to eat on the way.
Don't go hungry!
Got it!
Slow down!
Sorry for always bothering you.
It's no trouble at all.
Once it's fixed, we won't be in the dark.
Yeah, exactly.
Careful, Daren.
Yiran.
Director Ma.
You guys be careful.
Will do, will do.
Mom!
Xiaojie, Xiaoran.
Stop it, stop it.
You little brat!
I just did my makeup!
Morning, Juan.
Heading out?
Just running some errands.
Yangyang, careful with your hands.
Getting medicine for your aunt again?
Got a lot this time.
Come with me.
I just made some ice jelly.
Take a bowl for her to try.
I'm always bothering you.
Yiran.
I... I'd like to say a few more words to Yiran.
Yiran,
I, A Min,
am a dozen years older than you.
I don't know if what I'm saying is right.
Living in this world,
frankly, is just about experiencing things.
Not everyone
has to become what others consider successful.
In life, there are mountains you can't cross,
rivers you can't ford,
and distant places you can't reach.
But sometimes,
standing at the foot of a mountain,
watching the sun climb over the peak,
isn't that also a form of rising?
Watching the river flow by so quietly,
isn't that also a beautiful view?
No matter how great that distant place is,
if your family isn't there,
then it isn't home.
As for me, A Min,
I've been in this industry for over a decade.
My biggest realization is that
people are just like plants.
If they have no roots,
they are destined to drift.
So, Yiran,
sometimes in life,
you can't always just make the right choices.
You can also make choices you simply like.
A Min,
you usually don't say much.
But you've said so much today.
Thank you.
I'll remember this.
What are you doing standing here?
Where are you going? I'll give you a ride.
Paradise Funeral Home.
Let's go that way.
Let's go.
They're coming!
Run!
Stop!
Stop running!
Freeze!
If you want to go back to Shanghai,
then go.
This tiny place
can't hold someone with dreams.
What about you, Chen Baixi?
Have you learned
to make peace with this world?
Didn't I already tell you?
I've already been left behind.
I'm done fighting.
I'm lying flat.
It's raining so hard.
What are you doing standing outside?
Are you out of your mind?
None of your business.
Come on, cheer up.
Watch out!
The seatbelt's broken.
I was afraid you couldn't buckle it.
Let me help you fasten it.
What are you grinning at?
Was I grinning?
You were.
Let's go!
You're taking forever.